Finding Aid for School of Information (University of Michigan) Records 1901-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Course Material 1926-1995
  - 1935-1995
    - I.L.S. 628 (Dede) Analysis and Design of Subject Access Systems (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 628 (Warner) Analysis and Design of Subject Access Systems (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 630 Preservation of Information Resources (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 632 (Didier) Management of Libraries and Information Centers (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 632 (Dougherty) Management of Libraries and Information Centers (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 632 (Holland) Management of Libraries and Information Centers (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 637 Problems in Archival Administration 1994-1995 (Box 42)
    - L.S. 640 Classification and Indexing in the Social Sciences (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 644 Statistics for the Information Sciences (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 645 Measuring the Effectiveness of Library and Information Services (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 650 Concepts in Information Retrieval (Box 42)
    - L.S. 652 Logic of Mechanizing Information for Research 1956-1976 (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 652 Sources of Information in the Social Sciences 1993-1995 (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 654 Sources for Information in the Humanities (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 656 The Nature of Science and Engineering and Their Information Service Requirements (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 658 Sources of Information in the Medical and Health Sciences (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 660 (Cary) Sources of Business Information (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 660 (Foss) Sources of Business Information (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 662 Sources of Legal Information (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 664 Sources of Information in the Fine Arts (Box 42)
    - L.S. 675 Periodical Literature 1965-1985 (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 680 Technology-Based Information Systems in Organizations (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 689 (Hessler) Image and Information Systems and Technology (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 689 (Warner) Image and Information Systems and Technology (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 690 Field Experience and ED 302: Directed Teaching, Class Roster (Box 42)
    - L.S. 705 Seminar in Library Public Relations 1968 (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 723 Public Library Services (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 725 Community Information Resources and Services (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 730 (Beaver) Management of School Library Media Programs (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 730 (Garland) Management of School Library Media Programs (Box 42)
    - L.S. 736 Comparative Librarianship (Box 42)
    - L.S. 749 Business Information Services (Box 42)
    - L.S. 754 Documents of International Organizations 1961-1970 (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 753 Design of Information Products (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 755 Instruction in the Use of Information (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 760 Seminar on Information Policy (Box 42)
    - L.S. 761 Backgrounds of University Library Development (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 765 Seminar on Emerging Technologies (Box 42)
    - L.S. 771/772 Directed Reading 1962-1966 (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 780 On-line Systems For Access and Display (Box 42)
    - L.S. 781 Latin American Bibliography (Box 42)
    - L.S. 805 Advanced Studies in Cataloging 1970 (Box 42)
    - L.S. 809 Seminar in College Library Administration (Box 42)
    - L.S. 813/814 Seminar: Trends and Issues in Librarianship (Box 42)
    - L.S. 816 Seminar in Cataloging and Classification (Box 42)
    - L.S. Bibliography of English History and Literature (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 840 Research Methods in Library and Information Studies (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 841 Empirical Methods in Information and Library Studies (Box 42)
    - L.S. 852 Seminar n Applications of Computer Technology to Libraries (Box 42)
    - L.S. 854 Libraries and the Legislative Process (Box 42)
    - L.S. 870 Research Methods (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 888 Doctoral Seminar: Information Retrieval Systems (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 888 Doctoral Seminar: Information Visualization (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 888 Doctoral Seminar: On Approaches To The Understanding of Information Needs, Seeking, and Use (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 888 Doctoral Seminar: On-line Public Access: Electronic Publication Paradigm Shift (Box 42)
    - I.L.S. 888 Doctoral Seminar: Relevance and Beyond (Box 42)
    - Record of Courses Discontinued (for those courses without an individual folder) 1956-1981 (Box 42)
- Archived School of Information Website
  The Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the School of Information. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the School. The website series is arranged chronologically and includes content captured by the Internet Archive starting in 1997 as well as captures provided by Bentley Library archivists in 2002, 2003, and 2008. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Home Page
    - 1997-[ONGOING]
      (These copies were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
    - May 15, 2002, .ZIP file
    - May 22, 2003, .ZIP file
    - June 4, 2008, .ZIP file
    - 2010-[ONGOING]
  - Related materials: degree requirements, curricula, centers and institutes, 2010-[ONGOING]
- Faculty Files 1927-1996
  The Faculty Files series (1.75, 1927-1996) are personnel files maintained in the Dean's office on faculty members. All files in the record group are for inactive faculty members. Materials vary from file to file but, often include correspondence, curriculum vitae, course syllabi, news clippings, and grant proposals and background materials.
  - Hsu, James 1934-1936 (Box 44)
  - Jackson, Eugene 1964 (Box 44)
  - Joeckel, C.B. 1926-1931, 2 folders (Box 44)
  - Kaiser, Walter Herbert 1948-1951, 2 folders (Box 44)
  - Kochen, Manfred 1968-1978, 3 folders (Box 44)
  - Kreuz, Loretta B. 1964-1969 (Box 44)
  - Larson, John 1965-1970 (Box 44)
  - Magrill, Rose Mary 1970-1981, 2 folders (Box 44)
  - McAllister, S.W. 1943-1952 (Box 44)
  - McCoy, Iola 1964-1966 (Box 44)
  - McCrossman, John Anthony 1968-1982 (Box 45)
  - McDiarmid, E.W., Jr. 1935-1937 (Box 45)
  - McHale, Cecil John 1948-1970, 2 folders (Box 45)
  - Muller, Robert 1964-1970 (Box 45)
  - Pao, Miranda Lee 1987-1993 (Box 45)
  - Searson, Marilyn 1975-1976 (Box 45)
  - Shaw 1951-1962 (Box 45)
  - Strasser, Alexander 1976-1977 (Box 45)
  - Quenzel, Carrol 1964-1966 (Box 45)
  - Wagman, Frederick 1964-1979 (Box 45)
  - Warren, Althea Hester 1949-1958 (Box 45)
  - Wasserman, Paul 1960-1964 (Box 45)
  - Wead, Eunice 1828-1950 (Box 45)
Related Material
The School of Information printed materials, including catalogs, newsletters, brochures, and directories are cataloged and described separately.
The Bentley Historical Library holds personal paper of several School of Information administrators and faculty, including William Warner Bishop, Wallace Bonk, Rudolph Gjelsness, Russell Bidlack and Robert M. Warner
A researcher may also want to consult the School's website for current information on academic programs, courses, faculty, news and events, and research projects. The website is available at: http://www.si.umich.edu.